geekdashboard.com 2019-05-16

# Privacy Policy

**Last Updated: 12 February 2019**

###  Introduction

This privacy policy (“ **Policy** ”) describes how **Geek Dashboard** (“ **Company,** ” “ **we,** ” and “ **our** ”) processes, collects, uses and shares personal data when using this website https://www.geekdashboard.com (the “ **Site** ”). Please read the following information carefully to understand our practices regarding your personal data and how we will process data.

### 1\. Purposes of Processing

 **What is personal data?**

We collect information about you in a range of forms, including personal data. As used in this Policy, “personal data” is as defined in the General Data Protection Regulation, this includes any information which, either alone or in combination with other information we process about you, identifies you as an individual, including, for example, your name, email address and telephone number.

#### Why do we need your personal data?

We will only process your personal data in accordance with applicable data protection and privacy laws. We need certain personal data in order to provide you with access to the Site. If you registered with us to submit a guest post, you will have been asked to tick to agree to provide this information in order to access, submit and edit our content. This consent provides us with the legal basis we require under applicable law to process your data. You maintain the right to withdraw such consent at any time. If you do not agree to our use of your personal data in line with this Policy, please do not use our Site.

### 2\. Collecting Your Personal Data

We collect information about you in the following ways:

 **Information You Give Us.** This includes:

  * the personal data you provide when you register to use our Site, including your name, email address, username, password, social media profile links, and author bio.
  * the personal data that may be contained when you post a comment on our articles and subscribe to our newsletters.
  * the personal data you provide in connection with our rewards program and other promotions we run on the Site;
  * the personal data you provide when you report a problem with our Site or when we provide you with customer support;
  * the personal data you provide when you correspond with us by phone, email or otherwise.

#### Automated Decision Making and Profiling.

We do not use your personal data for the purposes of automated decision-making. However, we may do so in order to fulfill obligations imposed by law, in which case we will inform you of any such processing and provide you with an opportunity to object.

### 3\. Cookies

 **What are the cookies?**

We may collect information using “cookies.” Cookies are small data files stored on the hard drive of your computer or mobile device by a website. We may use both session cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent cookies (which stay on your computer or mobile device until you delete them) to provide you with more personal and interactive experience on our Site.

We use two broad categories of cookies: (1) first party cookies, served directly by us to your computer or mobile device, which are used only by us to recognize your computer or mobile device when it revisits our Site (used to automatically login our users while submitting the guest post); and (2) third party cookies, which are served by service providers on our Site, and can be used by such service providers to recognize your computer or mobile device when it visits other websites.

 **Cookies we use**

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

Our Site uses the following types of cookies for the purposes set out below:

 ** _Functionality Cookies:_**

These cookies allow our Site to remember choices you make when you use our Site, such as remembering your login details. The purpose of these cookies is to provide you with a more personal experience and to avoid you having to re-enter your preferences every time you visit our Site.

 ** _Analytics and Performance Cookies:_**

These cookies are used to collect information about traffic to our Site and how users use our Site. **The information gathered does not identify any individual visitor**.It includes the number of visitors to our Site, the websites that referred them to our Site, the pages they visited on our Site, what time of day they visited our Site, whether they have visited our Site before, and other similar information.] [We use this information to help operate our Site more efficiently, to gather broad demographic information and to monitor the level of activity on our Site.

We use Google Analytics for this purpose. Google Analytics uses its own cookies. It is only used to improve how our Site works. [You can find out more information about Google Analytics cookies here](https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies)

You can find out more about how Google protects your data [here](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html).

You can prevent the use of Google Analytics relating to your use of our Site by downloading and installing the browser plugin available [via this link](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB)

 ** _Targeted and advertising cookies:_**

These cookies track your browsing habits to enable us to show advertising which is more likely to be of interest to you. These cookies use information about your browsing history to group you with other users who have similar interests. Based on that information, and with our permission, third-party advertisers can place cookies to enable them to show adverts which we think will be relevant to your interests while you are on third party websites.]

You can disable cookies which remember your browsing habits and target advertising at you by visiting [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices). If you choose to remove targeted or advertising cookies, you will still see adverts but they may not be relevant to you. Even if you do choose to remove cookies by the companies listed at the above link, not all companies that serve online behavioral advertising are included in this list, and so you may still receive some cookies and tailored adverts from companies that are not listed.

 ** _OneSignal Cookies:_**

We use OneSignal to send notifications to your web browser after your consent. These notifications include our new posts, promotions and affiliate offers.

You can know more about OneSignal privacy policy here

https://onesignal.com/privacy_policy

 ** _Social Media Cookies:_**

These cookies are used when you share information using a social media sharing button or “like” button on our Site or you link your account or engage with our content on or through a social networking website such as Facebook, Twitter or Google+. The social network will record that you have done this.

 **Disabling cookies**

You can typically remove or reject cookies via your browser settings. In order to do this, follow the instructions provided by your browser (usually located within the “settings,” “help” “tools” or “edit” facility). Many browsers are set to accept cookies until you change your settings.

If you do not accept our cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of our Site. For example, we may not be able to recognize your computer or mobile device and you may need to log in every time you visit our Site.

### 4\. Advertising

We may use other companies to serve third-party advertisements when you visit and use the Site. These companies may collect and use click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over during your visits to the Site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of interest to you. These companies typically use tracking technologies to collect this information. Other companies’ use of their tracking technologies is subject to their own privacy policies.

### 5\. Affiliates

Geek Dashboard uses the Amazon associates program for promoting products from Amazon through affiliate links. Whenever a user buys a product from those links, we earn a commission. However, we only recommend relevant products that have high ratings and positive reviews.

Along with Amazon associates, we also use many affiliate programs like Commission Junction, Share a Sale, ClickBank etc to promote products we personally use and test. The commissions we earn from these purchases helps us in paying our bills and generate more useful content for our readers.

### 6\. Using Your Personal Data

 **We may use your personal data as follows:**

  * to operate, maintain, and improve our Site and  products;
  * to manage your account, including to communicate with you regarding your account, if you have an account on our Site;
  * to operate and administer our rewards program and other promotions you participate in on our Site;
  * to respond to your comments and questions and to provide customer service;
  * to send information including technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * with your consent, to send you marketing e-mails about upcoming promotions, and other news, including information about products and services offered by us and our affiliates. You may opt-out of receiving such information at any time: such marketing emails tell you how to “opt-out.” Please note, even if you opt out of receiving marketing emails, we may still send you non-marketing emails. Non-marketing emails include emails about your account with us (if you have one) and our business dealings with you;
  * for analysis and study services; and
  * as described in the “Sharing of your Personal Data” section below.

### 7\. Sharing Your Personal Data

 **We may share your personal data as follows:**

  *  **Third Parties Designated by You.** We may share your personal data with third parties where you have provided your consent to do so.
  *  **Our** **Third Party Service Providers**. We may share your personal data with our third party service providers who provide email delivery service. We use mailchimp to send promotional emails and you can know more about their privacy policy here https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/ .Your comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

### 8\. Third Party Sites

Our Site may contain links to third party websites and features. This Policy does not cover the privacy practices of such third parties. These third parties have their own privacy policies and we do not accept any responsibility or liability for their websites, features or policies. Please read their privacy policies before you submit any data to them.

In few of our articles, we embed third party websites features and these third party website features include Facebook like, Facebook Share, Twitter Tweets, Likes, Retweets, Google +1, YouTube videos and Github gists. While using these features, you agree to the privacy policies of the respective websites.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### 9\. User-Generated Content

You may share personal data with us when you submit user generated content to our Site, including via our rewards program and blog comments. Please note that any information you post or disclose on our Site will become public information, and will be available to other users of our Site and to the general public. We urge you to be very careful when deciding to disclose your personal data, or any other information, on our Site. Such personal data and other information will not be private or confidential once it is published on our Site.

When you leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

If you provide feedback to us, we may use and disclose such feedback on our Site, provided we do not associate such feedback with your personal data. If you have provided your consent to do so, we may post your first and last name along with your feedback on our Site. We will collect any information contained in such feedback and will treat the personal data in it in accordance with this Policy.

### 10\. International Data Transfer

Your information, including personal data that we collect from you, may be transferred to, stored at and processed by us outside the country in which you reside, where data protection and privacy regulations may not offer the same level of protection as in other parts of the world. By accepting this Policy, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Policy.

### 11\. Security

We seek to use reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures to protect personal data within our organization. Unfortunately, no transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be completely secure, and transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us.

### 12\. Retention

We will only retain your personal data as long reasonably required for you to use the Site until you close your account unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (for example for regulatory purposes).

### 13\. Our Policy on Children

Our Site is/are not directed to children under 16. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with information without their consent, he or she should contact us. We will delete such information from our files as soon as reasonably practicable.

### 14\. Your Rights

  *  **Opt-out.** You may contact us anytime to opt-out of (i) direct marketing communications; (ii) automated decision-making and/or profiling; (iii) our collection of sensitive personal data; (iv) any new processing of your personal data that we may carry out beyond the original purpose; or (v) the transfer of your personal data outside the EEA. Please note that your use of some of the Site may be ineffective upon opt-out.
  *  **Access.** You may access the information we hold about you at any time via your profile/account or by contacting us directly.
  *  **Amend.** You can also contact us to update or correct any inaccuracies in your personal data.
  *  **Erase and forget.** In certain situations, for example, when the information we hold about you is no longer relevant or is incorrect, you can request that we erase your data.

If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact us. In your request, please make clear: (i) **what** personal data is concerned; and (ii) **which of the above rights** you would like to enforce. For your protection, we may only implement requests with respect to the personal data associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable and in any event, within one month of your request. Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record-keeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting such change or deletion.

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### 15\. Complaints

We are committed to resolving any complaints about our collection or use of your personal data. If you would like to make a complaint regarding this Policy or our practices in relation to your personal data, please contact us at [contact@geekdashboard.com](mailto:contact@geekdashboard.com)

We will reply to your complaint as soon as we can and in any event, within 30 days. We hope to resolve any complaint brought to our attention, however, if you feel that your complaint has not been adequately resolved, you reserve the right to contact your local data protection supervisory authority

### Contact Information

We welcome your comments or questions about this Policy. You may contact us in writing at

Or you can visit us in person at

Office No: 9, 4th Floor, A – Block,  
Guptas Square, Kurnool Road,  
Ongole, Andhra Pradesh – India

Phone: +91 9849033137
